Edward Corsi Papers
Edward Corsi Papers
- Writings
  - Reports
    - Unemployment Insurance in the Second Year of War, Annual Report 1943, Albany, 1944 (Box 30)
  - Speeches (* indicates also a radio broadcast)
    - re: Italian contributions to American life, [1938]; typescript (Box 31)
    - "Statement...on Unemployment Insurance", 1939, March 9; typescript (Box 31)
    - re: need for revision of immigration and naturalization laws, to National Council on Naturalization and Citizenship, 1939, [April 21]; typescript carbon revised; news release (Box 31)
    - re: role of political parties in augmenting social welfare, to New York State Conference on Social Work at Rochester, 1939, [October 18]; 1939 July 25;; 1939, September 21; typescript revised; correspondence (Box 31)
    - re: need to raise unemployment insurance benefits, 1939, November 15; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - * re: Italian Welfare League, 1939, December 21; typescript and typescript carbon; includes correspondence, December 15-26, 1939 (Box 31)
    - re: antagonism toward the foreign-born, [1939?]; typescript revised and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - "America and the Foreign Born", [ca. 1941?]; typescript revised and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - "American Unity in the Present Crisis", [ca. 1941?]; typescript revised (Box 31)
    - re: antagonism toward the foreign-born, [ca. 1941?]; typescript revised and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - re: compulsory military service, [ca. 1941?]; typescript revised (Box 31)
    - "Council for Democracy Rally", [ca. 1941?]; typescript revised and typescript carbon revised (Box 31)
    - re: the foreign-born, to American Common Council, [ca. 1941?]; typescript revised and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - re: the Italians of New York City, [ca. 1941?]; holograph revised and typescript revised (Box 31)
    - "Our Italian Neighbors", [ca. 1941?]; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - "Testimony Given on Behalf of Organizations Concerned with the Welfare of Americans of German and Italian Stock, Before the President's Committee on Fair Employment Practice", 1942, February 16; typescript carbon; includes correspondence, February 7-10, 1942 (Box 31)
    - re: National Child Labor Committee, 1944, February 18; typescript carbon revised and printed material (Box 31)
    - "Syracuse Speech", 1944, August 23; typescript, typescript carbon and printed material (Box 31)
    - * re: Servicemen's Readjustment Act of 1944, 1944, September 15, 18, 21; typescript carbon; correspondence (Box 31)
    - "Child Labor in New York State", 1944, November 16; typescript revised (Box 31)
    - "Fire and Death Still Lurk in the Building Code", [1944?]; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - re: New York State laws for working women and children, 1945, February 6; typescript revised (Box 31)
    - statement before the House of Representatives Foreign Affairs Committee in favor of House Joint Resolution no. 99, 1945, April 11; printed material (Box 31)
    - * re: Retail Trade Minimum Wage Board, 1945, October 3; printed material (Box 31)
    - "What is Ahead for Labor", 1945, November 8-9; 1946, February 5, 13; typescript revised, correspondence (Box 31)
    - "Minimum Wage Laws of New York State", 1946, January 11; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - re: New York Young Republican Club, 1946, January 24; printed material (Box 31)
    - * Foreign Language Press Film Critics' Circle, 1946, March 4; typescript carbon revised (Box 31)
    - * re: Red Cross Drive, 1946, March 21, 25; typescript; correspondence (Box 31)
    - re: prevention of accidents in industry, at New York Safety Conference, 1946, March 26; typescript and printed material (Box 31)
    - re: need for revision of immigration laws, to National Conference of Social Work, 1946, May 23; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - re: industrial record of New York State, to Associated Industries of New York State, Inc., 1946, May 28, 29; typescript; correspondence (Box 31)
    - Central Union Label Council of Greater New York, 1946, [August 9]; typescript revised and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - Workers Defense League honoring Dr. Frank Graham, 1946, November 2; printed material (Box 31)
    - Graduating class, Joint Industrial Board of Electrical Industry, 1947, January 15; typescript (Box 31)
    - re: displaced persons, to Jewish Labor Committee Convention, 1947, February 1; typescript and printed material (Box 31)
    - Herman Winter Testimonial Dinner, Bakery and Confectionery Workers, 1947, February 22; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - Italian-American Grocers Association of Greater New York, Inc., 1947, February; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - "The Italian Immigrant's Contribution to American Life", 1947, March 28; printed material (Box 31)
    - re: silver anniversary of the New York Women's Trade Union League, 1947, March; typescript (Box 31)
    - "Testimony on Italian Peace Treaty before United States Senate Committee on Foreign Relations", 1947, April 30; typescript (Box 31)
    - New York State Fund Dinner, 1947, May 22; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - re: International Association of Public Employment Services, 1947, May 26; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - re: New York State Federation of Labor - 84th annual convention, 1947, July 15; typescript and printed material (Box 31)
    - * "Labor Day Address", 1947, August 31; typescript carbon revised and printed material (Box 31)
    - re: displaced persons, 1947, November 27; typescript, typescript carbon, and notes (Box 31)
    - "Statement for Journal of Commerce", 1947, November; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - Joint Industry Board - Electrical Industry-Central Needle Trades High School- Graduation ceremonies, 1947, December 12; printed material (Box 31)
    - statement re: the peace treaty with Italy, 1947; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - re: New York State Industrial Department, Binghamton, [1947?]; typescript (Box 31)
    - re: Italian-American Grocers Association, 1948, March; typescript (Box 31)
    - * "Message...to Italy" re: Communists, 1948, April 15; typescript (Box 31)
    - re: revision of immigration laws, National Conference of Social Workers, 1948, April 21; typescript revised, typescript carbon, printed material (Box 31)
    - "Eastern Seaboard Apprenticeship Conference", 1948, June 24-26; typescript revised and printed material (Box 31)
    - re: displaced persons' camps, 1948, September 11; typescript (Box 31)
    - re: election, 1948, [November 1?]; typescript revised and typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - "Statement...Before the Subcommittee to Investigate Immigration and Naturalization of the United States Senate Judiciary Committee", 1948, November 16; typescript carbon revised and printed material (Box 31)
    - re: New York State Labor Department, [1948]; typescript carbon (Box 31)
    - "Governor Dewey's Labor Record in New York State,", [1948]; typescript revised; correspondence, May 7, 1948 (Box 31)
    - "Raymond P. Fisher Dinner", 1949, February 17; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - re: economic outlook for New York City, to United Neighborhood Houses of New York, Inc., 1949, May 3, 11, 18; typescript and typescript carbon; correspondence (Box 32)
    - "Labor Day Address", 1949, September 5; typescript and printed material (Box 32)
    - * "Address...at Republican Rally.. ", 1949, October 29; printed material (Box 32)
    - Republican rallies, 1949, November 3, 5; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - "Regional Conference on Labor Statistics and Women in Industry, New York City", 1950, May 23-25; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - re: Queensboro Council for Social Welfare, 1950, May; publicity, printed material (Box 32)
    - * re: One-hundredth anniversary of Giuseppe Garibaldi's visit to United States, 1950, July 8; typescript (Box 32)
    - "The Administration's Labor Record", 1950, July 27; typescript carbon and typescript carbon revised (Box 32)
    - "...to New York State Federation of Labor", 1950, August 2; draft, typescript and holograph (Box 32)
    - re: International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers honorary dinner, 1950, September 23; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - re: progress of workers in the last fifty years, 1950, November 5; typescript revised (Box 32)
    - "Retreat from Freedom" re: Wendell Willkie, 1951, February 19; typescript and typescript revised (Box 32)
    - "...State Employees Group for the Greater New York Fund", 1951, April 18; typescript (Box 32)
    - "Remarks...at the Opening of the Columbus Hospital Wing", 1951, May 6, 8; typescript revised, typescript carbon; correspondence (Box 32)
    - "Remarks...New York Typographical Union No. 6 Memorial Meeting...", 1951, May 20; printed material (Box 32)
    - re: International Longshoremen's Associations Convention, 1951, July 24; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - "Address...the American and European friends of Ort", 1951, November 27; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - Campaign speech?, [1951]; typescript revised (Box 32)
    - re: New York State's preparations for defense, [1951?]; typescript carbon revised (Box 32)
    - "Address to Community Leaders of Utica", 1952, April 17; typescript carbon revised (Box 32)
    - "Summary of Speech...Before a Meeting of the Association of Justices of Delaware County", 1952, April 26; typescript carbon rev (Box 32)
    - "Statement to the President's Commission on Immigration and Naturalization", 1952, October 1; printed material (Box 32)
    - "Report to New York State Joint Legislative Committee", 1952, October 11; typescript carbon revised (Box 32)
    - "Address...to the Hebrew Immigrant Aid Society, Council of Organizations", 1952, October 26; printed material (Box 32)
    - re: campaign, [1952]; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - "Remarks...at Testimonial Dinner to George Meany", 1953, April 25; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - "Address...Before New York State Apprentice Conference", 1953, October 29; printed material revised (Box 32)
    - "...At the Dinner of the Free Europe Committee, Inc., Carnegie Endowment International Center", 1954, April 30; typescript revised and typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - "...91st Annual Convention of the New York State Federation of Labor", 1954, July 20; printed material (Box 32)
    - "...Meeting of Malone Kiwanis Club...", 1954, September 7; printed material (Box 32)
    - "Report of Legislative Committee of the International Association of Government Labor Officials", 1954, [September]; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - "...the Ninth Annual Federal Safety Conference, Chicago, Ill.", 1954, October 19; typescript revised (Box 32)
    - "Social Horizons in New York State, Statement...Before the Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor Conditions", 1954, December 14; printed material (Box 32)
    - "For Utica TV show," re: Republicans, [1954]; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - "Face the Nation," CBS Television, re: State Department and immigration, 1955, April 17; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - statement about immigration before United States Senate committee, 1955, [April]; typescript revised (Box 32)
    - "The Impact of International Tensions on People," at National Conference of Social Work, 1955, June 1; publicity, printed material (Box 32)
    - Committee on Immigration and Naturalization of Allegheny County, Dinner Meeting, 1956, January 24; holograph and typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - "America and the Immigrant", Undated; typescript (Box 32)
    - "for Journal American," re: alien enemies, Undated; typescript carbon (Box 32)
    - Fourth Annual Columbian Republican League Convention of New York State, Undated; typescript revised (Box 32)
    - re: graduation and Italians, Undated; typescript revised (Box 32)
    - re: Republicans, Undated; notes, typescript (Box 32)
    - re: Secretary of Labor Frances Perkins and her criticism of workmen's compensation in New York State, Undated; holograph (Box 32)
    - "Taped interview about Italians in America", Undated; typescript (Box 32)
    - *"A Tribute to the Contributions of the Foreign Born to America", Undated; holograph (Box 32)
  - Unidentified writings
    - re: New York State Mediation Board, January 25, 1949; fragment, typescript (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous in Italian, Undated; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 32)
  - Writings of others
    - Books
      - Untitled, by Michael Fiaschetti, re: crime-fighting, undated; typescript revised (Box 33)
    - Reports
      - "And Proud of It," by Louis Adamic, undated; typescript carbon (Box 33)
      - Untitled, re: Massari, a sculptor, undated; typescript (Box 33)
- Activities
  - Alien Enemy Hearing Board, correspondence and legal cases, May 7, 1941-February 11, 1944 (Box 33)
  - American Federation of International Institutes
    - Correspondence
      - November 1941-January 11, 1950, 3 folders (Box 33)
      - 1950-1958, undated, 4 folders (Box 34)
    - Agenda and proposals, 1942-1965; undated; typescript and typescript carbon; 2 folders (Box 34)
    - Minutes and reports, 1942-1965; undated; printed material; 5 folders (Box 35)
  - American Immigration Conference, 1954; 1958-1961; proposals and reports, printed material, correspondence (October 1959 only) (Box 35)
  - American Museum of Immigration
    - Correspondence, September 26, 1954-November 29, 1965 (Box 36)
    - Agenda and proposals, February-November, 1956; typescript and typescript carbon (Box 36)
    - Reports, 1955-1965; printed material; 3 folders (Box 36)
  - American Resettlement Council for Italian Refugees
    - Correspondence, April 26-November 3, 1954 (Box 36)
    - Reports, April-December 1954; printed material (Box 36)
  - American War-Community Services, Inc.
    - Correspondence, August 2, September 18, 1944 (Box 36)
    - Minutes, June 1-August 5, 1943; typescript carbon (Box 36)
  - Arbitration cases
    - Air La-Carte, Inc., and Local 295, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, January 21-April 29, 1963 (Box 37)
    - Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America, Local 150-F and Joseph A. Kaplan & Co., Inc., May 9, 1961-March 2, 1962 (Box 37)
    - Angelo of Mulberry Street, Inc., and Locals 8, 9, 1, and 711, January 9-November 7, 1962 (Box 37)
    - Barber's Union, Local 1 and Anthony's Barber Shop and Victor Barber Shop, July 13-September 17, 1965 (Box 37)
    - Barber's Union, Local 1, with Dezemler, December 1-17, 1964 (Box 37)
    - Bates Chevrolet Corporation and Local 259, United Automobile Workers, August 29, 1963-March 20, 1964 (Box 37)
    - Burning Embers, Inc. and Local 164, Bartenders, Hotel and Restaurant Workers, October 27, 1965-January 19, 1966 (Box 37)
    - Carol Management Corp. and Local 32B, Building Service Employees International Union, August 19-November 3, 1965 (Box 37)
    - Cases cancelled, 1961 (Box 37)
    - Collective Bargaining Agreement between Journeymen Barbers International Union, Local 1, AFL-CIO and various barbershop owners, October 1, 1964-April 13, 1965 (Box 37)
    - Collective Bargaining Agreement between Journeymen Barbers International Union, Local 11, AFL-CIO and various barbershop owners, June 10, 1964-January 5, 1965 (Box 37)
    - Columbia Metal Products Co., Inc. and Local 400, Sheet Metal Workers, June 27-October 23, 1962 (Box 37)
    - Consolidated Diesel Electric Corporation and United Automobile Workers, Local 259, July 9-November 25, 1964 (Box 37)
    - Consolidated Wholesale Florists Corp. and Local 277, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, October 24, 1962-March 1, 1963 (Box 37)
    - Continental Baking Company, March 20-24, 1961 (Box 37)
    - Dan's Bakery and Local 350, Bakery and Confectionery Workers, February 21- December 10, 1963 (Box 37)
    - D'Aquila Brothers Construction Co., Inc., July 1, 1959-February 9, 1962 (Box 37)
    - David Livingston as President of District 65, R.W.D.S.U. (Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union), AFL-CIO and Lewis Supply Co., Inc., February 26- September 14, 1964 (Box 37)
    - David Livingston as President of District 65, R.W.D.S.U., AFL-CIO, and Wholesale Distributors Association, Inc., March 10-June 15, 1964 (Box 37)
    - District 65, R.W.D.S.U., AFL-CIO and Wholesale Distributors Association, Inc., on behalf of Capitol Dry Goods, January 6-November 30, 1965 (Box 37)
    - Federal Bias Corporation and Local 252, Textile Workers, May 24-October 9, 1963 (Box 37)
    - Fifth Avenue Hospital, July 15, 1959-January 18, 1962 (Box 37)
    - General Baking Co. and Local 50, Bakery and Confectionery Workers, February 5, 1962-April 5, 1963 (Box 37)
    - General Baking Co. and Local 50, Bakery and Confectionery Workers, January 7-March 23, 1964 (Box 38)
    - General Bronze Corporation and Local 455, Shopmens union, November 8, 1962-April 5, 1963 (Box 38)
    - Golf Oldsmobile, Inc. and Local 259, United Auto Workers, January 4-25, 1963 (Box 38)
    - Hahns Creameries, Inc. and Local 277, I.B.T., August 24-September 12, 1962 (Box 38)
    - Hooven Letter, September 14-October 29, 1959 (Box 38)
    - International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Local 282 and Colonial Sand and Stone Co., July 11-November 3, 1958 (Box 38)
    - International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers, Local 317, and Foster Refrigerator Corporation, May 22-September 14, 1962 (Box 38)
    - Joe and Pat's Barbershop and Local 15, Barbers Union, May 2, 1962-March 6, 1963 (Box 38)
    - Journeymen Barbers International Union of America, AFL-CIO, Local 3 and various barbershop owners, October 23, 1965 (Box 38)
    - Journeymen Barbers International Union of America, Locals 1 & 3 and Broadway Master Barbers Association, Inc., April 28, 1961- March 23, 1962 (Box 38)
    - Ketchum & Co., Inc. and Local 815, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, August 19, 1960-January 12, 1961 (Box 38)
    - Lambert Products Co. and Textile Workers of America, March 16-May 6, 1964 (Box 38)
    - Legion Utensils Co., Inc. and Local 463, International Union of Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers, April 20-October 28, 1960 (Box 38)
    - Local 400, Sheet Metal Workers and United Metal Goods Manufacturing Co., Inc., April 2-May 24, 1965 (Box 38)
    - Local Electronics Corporation and Local 431 International Electrical Union, January 5-March 18, 1965 (Box 38)
    - Michelin Tire Corporation and Local 721, Retail Men's Wear Sporting Goods, August 2-December 16, 1960 (Box 38)
    - Monogram Tire and Battery Service and Local 721, Retail Men's Wear Sporting Goods, October 17-December 11, 1962 (Box 38)
    - Movielab, Inc. and Local 702, I.A.T.S.E.U., November 1963-March 20, 1964 (Box 38)
    - Mueller & Martens, Inc. Local 265, United Automobile Workers, August 23, 1962- January 21, 1964 (Box 38)
    - Penn Fruit Hills Supermarkets, Inc. and Local 1500, Retail Clerks, January 17- April 29, 1964 (Box 38)
    - Radio and Television Broadcast Engineers Union, Local 1212 and WMCA, Inc., August 3-17, 1960; 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Ratner Dairy Restaurant, July 23-October 21, 1958 (Box 39)
    - Roscar Products and Local 295, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, August 22-September 5, 1962 (Box 39)
    - Saltser and Weinsier, Inc., August 13, 1958-January 21, 1959 (Box 39)
    - Seeman Brothers, Inc., December 9, 1960- February 7, 1961 (Box 39)
    - Stouffer Restaurant-General File, November 9, 1959-May 17, 1960 (Box 39)
    - Suffolk Sand & Stone Corp. and Local 282, International Brotherhood of Teamsters, December 7, 1961-April 18, 1962 (Box 39)
    - Town and Country House and Home Service, Inc. and Local 307 Building Service Employees, August 25, 1964-January 7, 1965
    - United Mechanics, Local 150 and Cutting Room Appliances, Inc., June 10-July 14, 1958 (Box 39)
    - Waldorf-Astoria Barbershop and Journeymen Barbers Union, August 12, 1964-May 19, 1965 (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946; May 1957-November 24, 1964;; 1965; includes printed material (Box 39)
  - Big Brothers, Inc.
    - Correspondence, March 17, May 3, 1961 (Box 39)
    - Minutes and reports, printed material, August 31, 1960-April 13, 1961 (Box 39)
  - Campaign 1941, 1941-1942
    - Correspondence
      - September 3, 1941-August 4, 1942, includes 3 photographs; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Releases, October-November, 1941; typescript (Box 40)
    - Reports, undated; typescript and holograph (Box 40)
  - Campaign 1950
    - Correspondence
      - A, September 27-November 1, 1950 (Box 40)
      - B, September 14-December 14, 1950 (Box 40)
      - C, September 3-November 4, 1950 (Box 40)
      - D-E, September 14-November 9, 1950 (Box 40)
      - Education-Joint Teachers, September 26-November 6, 1950; 2 folders (Box 41)
      - Ellis, John, October 5-26, 1950 (Box 41)
      - F-G, September 13-November 14, 1950 (Box 41)
      - H-I, September 12-November 13, 1950 (Box 41)
      - J-K, September 20-November 2, 1950 (Box 41)
      - L, June 16-November 28, 1950 (Box 41)
      - M, September 27-November 6, 1950 (Box 41)
      - Memoranda, September 30-November 2, 1950 (Box 42)
      - N-O, September 26-November 3, 1950 (Box 42)
      - P-Q, September 27-November 2, 1950 (Box 42)
      - R, September 15-November 8, 1950 (Box 42)
      - Releases, October 6-November 3, 1950 (Box 42)
      - S, September 12-November 6, 1950 (Box 42)
      - T-V, October 10-November 3, 1950; May 16, 1952 (Box 42)
      - W-Z, October 4-November 6, 1950; June 6, 1952 (Box 42)
      - Acknowledgments, November 8-December 13, 1950 (Box 42)
      - Expenses, November 15, 1950-August 22, 1951 (Box 42)
      - Personal, September 11, 1950-April 17, 1953 (Box 42)
      - Miscellaneous, September 25, 1950-April 24, 1953; undated (Box 42)
    - Phonotape, interview with Corsi about campaign (Box 42)
    - J. Raymond Jones file, October 24, 1950; typescript (Box 43)
    - Sean P. Keating file, October 13-19, 1950; correspondence (Box 43)
    - Ferdinand Pecora file, June 1929-October 1950; typescript and printed material (Box 43)
    - Traffic-Parking file, January-August 1950; typescript (Box 43)
    - Newspaper clippings
      - Corsi Campaign, September 14-November 3, 1950 (Box 43)
      - Editorials about Corsi, September 13-October 5, 1950; undated (Box 43)
      - Civil Service Leader, October 10-25, 1950 (Box 43)
      - Daily Compass, September 18-November 3, 1950 (Box 43)
      - New York Herald Tribune
        - September 24-October 31, 1950, 3 folders (Box 43)
        - November 1-3, 1950 (Box 44)
      - New York Journal American, September 22-October 6, 1950 (Box 44)
      - New York Post, September 22-October 31, 1950; 2 folders (Box 44)
      - World Telegram
        - September 13-October 11, 1950 (Box 44)
        - October 12-November 3, 1950; undated, 2 folders (Box 45)
      - Miscellaneous, August 30-November 28, 1950 (Box 45)
  - Campaign 1952
    - Published material, August-October 1952 (Box 45)
    - Morabito
      - Correspondence, May 14, 1952-January 31, 1953 (Box 45)
      - Brochures, 1948-1952 (Box 45)
  - The Committee for a Just Peace with Italy, Inc.
    - Correspondence, January 23, 1946-February 27, 1948 (Box 45)
    - Reports, April 1945-April 1947; printed material (Box 45)
    - Reports, May 1947-July 1948; printed material (Box 46)
  - Cooperative for American Remittances to Europe, Inc. (CARE)
    - Correspondence, October 27, 1947-October 19, 1948 (Box 46)
  - Thomas E. Dewey file
    - Correspondence, November 1938-February 1955; 3 folders (Box 46)
    - List of Delegates and Alternates to the Republican National Convention, 1948; typescript (Box 46)
    - Reports, January 1947-February 1950; typescript (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous, April 1944-November 1949; printed material (Box 46)
  - Home Relief Fund
    - Memoranda, undated; holograph and typescript carbon (Box 47)
    - Newspaper clipping scrapbooks
      - A, July 20-December 11, 1934; January 12-May 6, 1935 (Box 47)
      - B, February 3-August 9, 1934; May 11-July 23, 1935 (Box 47)
  - Immigration and Naturalization